<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Relay Chain on Trustless future is tomorrow - Husni's personal site</title><link>https://ical10.github.io/tags/relay-chain/</link><description>Recent content in Relay Chain on Trustless future is tomorrow - Husni's personal site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 22:20:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ical10.github.io/tags/relay-chain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Substrate-based Relay Chain Deployment Setup</title><link>https://ical10.github.io/posts/post-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ical10.github.io/posts/post-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="run-a-validator-node"&gt;Run A Validator Node&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id="initial-set-up"&gt;Initial Set-up&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id="requirements"&gt;Requirements&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common way for a beginner to run a validator is on a cloud server running Linux. You may choose whatever VPS provider that you prefer. As OS it is best to use a recent Debian Linux. For this guide we will be using Ubuntu 22.04, but the instructions should be similar for other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="reference-hardware"&gt;Reference Hardware&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transaction weights in Polkadot are benchmarked on reference hardware. We ran the benchmark on VM instances of two major cloud providers: Google Cloud Platform (GCP) and Amazon Web Services (AWS). To be specific, we used n2-standard-8 VM instance on GCP and c6i.4xlarge on AWS. It is recommended that the hardware used to run the validators at least matches the specs of the reference hardware in order to ensure they are able to process all blocks in time. If you use subpar hardware you will possibly run into performance issues, get less era points, and potentially even get slashed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>